♪ In the not-too
distant future
♪ Somewhere in time and space
♪ Mike Nelson and
his robot pals
♪ Are caught in
an endless chase
♪ Pursued by a woman
whose name is Pearl
♪ An evil gal who wants
to rule the world
♪ She threw a few
things in her purse
♪ And in her rocketship,
she hunts him
♪ All across the universe
I'll get you!
♪ I'll send him cheesy movies
♪ The worst I can
find, la, la, la
♪ He'll have to sit
and watch them all
♪ And I'll monitor
his mind, la, la, la
♪ Now, keep in mind,
Mike can't control
♪ Where the movies begin
or end, la, la, la
♪ He'll try to keep his sanity
♪ With the help of
his robot friends
Robot roll call.
- Cambot.
- You're on.
- Gypsy.
- Oh, my stars!
- Tom Servo.
- Check me out!
- Croooow!
- I'm different.
♪ If you're wondering how
he eats and breathes
♪ And other science
facts, la, la, la
♪ Just repeat to yourself,
It's just a show
♪ I should really just relax
♪ For Mystery Science
Theater 3000
(clanging vibrations)
Hi, everyone, Mike Nelson here
from the Satellite of Love.
As is often the case, we've
been sucked through a wormhole
and now we're sort of
drifting through time and,
I don't know, it's a bunch of...
(Tom Servo chanting)
Hey, do you have to
do that right now?
Yes.
Okay, well, then, two things.
Could you tell me
what you're doing?
And why you're dressed like the
guy in the Primo Beer label?
If you must know, Mike, I'm
practicing the traditional
tantric chant of the
Gyuto monks of Tibet.
With proper intonation, I
can harmonize my overtones
with the fundamental,
creating a chorus
of transcendent
music of pure bliss.
Five bucks says you can't.
You're on.
(Tom Servo inhales)
While Servo fails
here, I'll just tell you
that we seem to be hovering
over Ancient Rome, or something,
and now, we're...
(echoing chants)
Hey, well, listen to that.
I think you're on to
something there.
(chanting)
Hey, pretty doggone
transcendent, eh, Mike?
Well, namaste, buddy.
I'm gonna grab me a Sport Shake.
We'll be right back.
(upbeat pop music)
(chanting music)
(Tom Servo chanting)
(Tom Servo chuckles)
Shanti.
Look, a huge distracting thing!
(Tom Servo hoots)
What's up with
you, Mother of Pearl?
Oh, hi, Mike.
Let me bring you up to speed.
Brain Guy, can you
roll that clip?
Oh, certainly, I have
it queued up with my mind.
(electronic whirring)
(film reel rolling)
(electronic beep)
Welcome to Roman times.
Guards, seize them.
(dramatic tense music)
Well, there you have it,
and that was just
a few seconds ago.
I said seize them!
I, um, bid the guards
leave for the day.
What? Why?
I didn't think we'd need
them, with the festival and all.
Well, then, seize
them yourself!
Right!
Whoa, whoa, wait,
wait, wait, wait, wait!
- We're gods.
- Yes, gods.
Gods?
Yes, I am Apearlo.
Apearlo, right.
And he is Brainguyus.
Brainguyus, right,
how unimaginative.
Gods, among us.
They are not gods.
Where is your proof?
You wanna handle
this, Bleachy?
Not a problem,
Hold the old bean.
Behold, from nothing,
I produce this.
(all gasp)
Spoon.
(whispering)
No, something bigger.
Behold, from nothing,
I produce this.
(all gasp)
Bigger spoon.
No, something big,
something impressive!
Like what?
I don't know, like a
freezer, or something.
They wouldn't know what it is.
How 'bout a JVC turntable,
an elephant, or...
Mike, what can we conjure
for these Egyptian guys?
(chattering)
Okay, what about a pony?
Uh, I think a gas
grill would do it.
Or a pony, pony,
we're gonna say pony.
- A pony.
- Pony.
A pony.
I could make a nice
Shetland, I think.
To whom do you speak?
Oh, that's just Mike
and his idiot robots.
Gods. His idiot gods.
You communicate with
the gods in the stars?
Oh, yeah, you don't?
I mean, of course.
I know of this
average-looking man-god,
but what of the
golden spider duck
and the squat crimson pig?
(Pearl and Brain Guy chuckle)
Golden spider duck?
Hey, lady, try a proud
prancing reindeer,
or rotting stag or something.
Geez.
Aww, Mike.
She called you a crimson pig.
(Tom Servo chuckles)
Hey, wait a minute!
She thinks I'm
average looking.
Geez, oh boy.
Truly they are gods.
And we must prepare a
feast for these gods.
Our finest grappa.
Hey, don't skimp.
I'll have a red Sena
in a collins glass.
Your movie today Mike is
a little toxic spill called
"Horror of Party Beach".
Hey!
You guys got any "anti-paste-o"
around here or something?
Pearlo's gonna
starve to death here.
Gods! Sweet!
Golden spider duck.
How 'bout lean and
virile bull, or slender
love machine, lady.
Let's go. Come on.
We got movie sign.
Let's go.
(Crow yells)
(electronic vibrations
and crashes)
Oh, wow, the typewriter
was drunk when it
did that, huh?
He, he, horror!
Yeah, the horror at party
beach is Cindy's cheese dip.
(car engine)
Oh, another
Afrikaner beach movie.
You can't beat 'em.
Nope.
Ooo, must have edited the
crap out of this thing.
Nude driving, a new
fad among the teens.
Whoop, turned gray.
(upbeat beach music)
Sturgis, a city on the move.
Knock it off Gena.
Oh, and now it's white again.
Yeah!
Will he shift?
Will the wheel move?
(upbeat beach music)
Is that Jacques Brel coming up
behind him on the bike?
(Mike chuckles)
Uh, we're just running
to the Tom Thumb, honey.
Do we really need
the honor guard?
(upbeat beach music)
This man does
not wear a watch.
Hey, I'm nude.
Original soundtrack
not available.
You'll thank us.
(Crow chuckles)
So, what is additional
dialogue, anyway?
Oh, things like,
"Hey you, get off that."
And,
"Why not?"
Dialoque.
Ah, those are dog miles.
It's not that fast.
They landscaped the median
strip pretty nice now.
(Mike chuckles)
Horror at public beach.
Crappy movie parking here.
Heh, heh, heh, I love
chugging Cointreau on the beach.
Hon, lay off the booze today.
You've had enough.
Today, Tina and
alcohol are gonna have
a great cocktail.
My plastic hair is furious.
Ahhh!
You can booze it all you want,
but you better lay off me.
And you better
stand on your feet.
Because if you fall on your
face, I'm not gonna pick you up.
You understand?
When did you ever
have to carry me home?
I've always been able
to stand on my own two feet.
I never needed you.
And I never will.
- They wrote their own vows.
- Aww!
Say, what happened to the
campus big shot who'd
do anything for kicks?
Campus big shot's grown up.
Times have changed, Tina.
We're not a bunch
of kids anymore.
(Mike mumbles and
vibrates his voice)
You can do all the
partying you want.
You just better
stay out of my way.
Stop preaching.
I know about your plans.
Your experiments
in that laboratory.
Well let me tell you something.
I have a few experiments
of my own I'm just itching
to try.
And they don't have one
thing to do with test tubes
and bunsen burners.
Okay, Tina, if
that's what you want.
Eww, did you jiff?
Oh, Hank, what's
happening to us?
My little Hardware Hank.
When are you gonna get it
though your head that life isn't
just all fun and games?
Okay, okay. No more lectures.
We're not even talking
the same language anymore.
I speak Esperanto these days.
Alright, if that's the
way you want it, then you
just go on your way.
And I'll go mine.
We'll see who gets
the most out of life.
Oh, brother, you ain't
seen living 'til you seen
Tina swing.
Well, I'm gonna live too.
Fear of intimacy.
Exciting and new.
Sail away.
We're coming to the spot now.
When we get up out
there, give me a yell.
Spandau Ballet goes
on a fishing trip.
Okay, now.
Okay, boss.
Oh, it's an Exxon
training film.
Shouldn't we dump this in
a poor black neighborhood
or an Indian reservation?
I hope that's
Paula Cole in there.
Wow, that's really
booking to the bottom.
D'oh, immediately!
I'm sure we don't
do this kind of thing
these days, huh?
200 million flushes.
Oh, like this is gonna
hurt the precious ocean.
You know, you know, come to
think of it,
the ocean really sucks.
♪ Ave Mariiiiaaaa.
(Mike chuckles)
Just another
day at Love Canal.
He died gargling.
Is there something
wedged right in the back of
my tooth?
Can you see that?
Uhh, no.
Great!
I'm dead, and I'm breaking out.
I told him not to pick at it.
Hi!
On behalf of fish everywhere,
I hope you're
enjoying the picture.
(Tom Servo chuckles)
He's turning into
Oliver Reed's liver.
Oh, great.
What am I now?
A fried wonton?
Well!
Okay movie, we got it.
We got it.
Look, fish, there's
a whole ocean.
If you could swim somewhere
else while I'm transmogrifying.
I'm sure most radiation's
harmful eventually,
but ours does massive damage
in a matter of seconds.
Oooo! I bet ya that would
be good with drawn butter.
Of course, I'd eat my own
head with drawn butter.
(Mike chuckles)
You know, I've seen
so much horror at
Party Beach, I'm just
inured to it at this point.
Monster immediately
gets up and puts on
his metal machine music.
Eek!
Eh, it's a John Hurt mask.
The incredible,
horrible Mr. Limpet.
Yeah, all this talk about
swimming with the sharks.
Well, I do it every day, pal!
And your radiation-based
makeover is complete.
And we're looking at what now?
Oh-ho, is there anyone
who likes pickles as much
as I do?
(Crow chuckles)
Thing sleeps with the fishes.
(screeching)
Original soundtrack
by Nigel Tufnel.
(Crow groans)
To eleven.
And the mouse was
immediately pinned down
by a log.
You fish go on ahead.
You mustn't risk
your life for me.
Well, I know how it is though.
First thing in the morning,
I like to move a big log too.
(pulsing bubbles)
Alright men, raise
the mainsail--
My god, what's happened to me?
The monster stars in the
one-man version of
"Pirates of Penzance".
♪ I am the very model of
a modern Major-General
♪ I've information animal
Wow!
Men should not
have bikini areas.
No, no, no, no!
Taubs Holand's in
the middle there.
Oh!
Hey, that reminds me. Did
I bring my hot dog buns?
That's a female
buttocks, Gary.
I don't see the connection.
And children,
grandmas, everyone loves
to watch Suzy's butt.
It's the Suzy's butt festival.
(upbeat beach music)
Ow, ow, dancing hurts.
Ow, eek!
Hey, in the back
there, Drew Carey.
(upbeat beach music)
Save your money, guys.
The band bites.
Alright, men, park a
respectful distance away.
Impressive row of
Porto Pottys in the back there.
♪ Make a left, make a right
The Velvet Underground
hadn't really found
its heads yet.
How's it goin', car?
Well, into the U-Store-It, men.
Hey, why is that girl topless?
No, that's a g--
well, maybe...
Is it?
(upbeat beach music)
Jean-Paul Sartre's
motorcycle gang.
I believe in the
existential outlaw as hero.
That is why I travel
with these men.
White people attempting rhythm.
And it made sense to surrender.
The Germans were
very, very mean.
Ah, go to Vietnam.
Johnny Mathis and
the Conan O'Briens.
♪ 80, 90, gosh oh mighty
Hey, don't bogey that
Metrecal, man.
(upbeat pop music)
♪ I'm gonna get some wheels
♪ See how it feels to fly
Hi, director.
Hi, best boy.
I think she likes us.
♪ Hang on tight, baby
♪ It's alright, baby
♪ Here we go, go,
go, go, go, go
She could use a
few inhibitions.
It would do her good.
Ooo, she's blinding him
with the glare from
her midriff.
Arr, it's the belly
of the Great White Girl!
♪ Go baby, go baby, go!
It's a gang led
by Deepak Chopra.
♪ Funny little siren
♪ deh, deh, deh, deh, deh, deh
Hey, zipper butt.
Easy access.
freshness-dated.
♪ No more clover
♪ You lip sync real bad.
It's true. We suck.
There are girls here,
and that's upsetting us.
(upbeat music)
♪ Bye, bye, bye
Oh, goodbye friendly thin man.
Bye!
♪ Bye, bye, bye
(upbeat beach music)
I think she's
overcoming her shyness.
Mmmm, Dondi is
quite the stud.
Yeah, right.
Man, those hot Polish
immigrant girls.
(Crow rolls his tongue)
Johnny, I never let anyone
kiss me like this before.
My name's not Johnny.
What is it?
Irving.
Irving?
Heh, what's in a name?
Annie Brice and Scott
Hamilton make out.
Joy is crap.
Oh no, it's the silky
children. They're attacking!
Man takes his first
tentative steps out of
the water.
(water splashes)
Hey, guys, look up there.
It's The Rock.
(Mike chuckles)
(groaning)
Wow, a creature who's
face is 80% eye bag.
So, radiation has
a sense of humor?
Ahh, don't hit.
Elaine.
Kinda shook me up there.
You always go around
sneaking up on people?
Yep. Love it.
Well, I saw you just
staring out at the ocean, so I
thought I'd come
down and talk to you.
♪ Hey, everybody, yeah
Ha, ha, he is doing
something we did not rehearse,
and it is funny.
Ha, ha!
Come on Aunt Agnes.
You had enough. Let's go home.
♪ Yeah, everybody's doing
it, doing it, doing it
♪ Pickin' their
nose and chewing it.
♪ Chewing it, chewing it.
He thinks quite a
bit of you, you know.
He thinks you have
a great future.
As a white man.
Working with Dr. Gavin has
been just about the greatest
thing that's ever
happened to me, Elaine.
I'm happy.
But I still have
this problem with...
Bed wetting.
It's always on my mind.
Oh, I'm sure Tina will
come around to your way
of thinking.
She's bound to realize
what she has in you, Hank.
Umm, Hank.
Or, maybe she won't
realize, heh-heh.
Well, we'll see.
Jerk! Wow!
I think there's a tiny
string of sinew on you
we haven't seen yet.
♪ Shake it, shake it,
shake it, shake it, baby
♪ Shake it down
Music by the My Three Sons.
(upbeat beach music)
Look at me.
I am so Twyla Tharp.
(Crow chuckles)
(upbeat beach music)
I'm sure there's some
perfectly nice Tiger Sharks
just offshore who'd be
willing to eat these people.
Ahh! Ohh!
Ugh!
Ooo, she pulls a groin muscle.
Swing your partner do-si-do!
Now promenade!
You know I think what
they're really trying to say is
whoa whoa whoa whoa whoa.
But you're missing
the underlying message,
which is wiggle,
wiggle, wobble, wobble.
(upbeat beach music)
Do the Bruce Springsteen.
Anyway.
Hey, what's going on up there?
It's called fun.
I don't know. Let's go see.
(upbeat beach music)
There ain't no
cutting in, Rerun.
Come on. Right here.
In front of everyone.
Come on. Let's do it.
Yeah, I'd rather
see Rose Marie
and Morey Amsterdam
do The Lambada.
Little kids adore the
lovable town stripper.
I can't get this.
I can't. Stuck-uh!
I can't get this button off.
James Franciscus
is not pleased.
What are you doing?
What do you think I'm doing?
I am shaking what
my mother gave me,
thank you very much.
How can I star on Long
Street if I have a girlfriend
like you?
(intense horn music)
She doesn't want
to go with you.
Look, I don't think
that's any of your business.
♪ Chances are that I'll
kick your scrawny ass
(Mike chuckles)
Bernardo, no.
Ugh, I just had
radial keratotomy today.
Daddy, give me
an airplane ride.
Whee, ow, oh, another!
(Tom Servo chuckles)
Let's follow the couples.
Yes, let's go
where they're going.
(intense music)
You soiled my
cigarette pants, buster.
So, basically,
this crowd of people will
stand around to watch anything.
Hey, I don't think this
is a good idea, guys.
Let's think about this.
No, don't, don't, don't.
Oh, d'ow, my neck is broken.
(Tom Servo chuckles)
I don't know.
It just seems to me Lilian
Gish could take this gang.
(intense music)
Hang on,
let me toss a gay man at you.
There you go.
Batch man.
Ow!
I'm Marisa Tomei,
and I'm concerned.
I'm Joan Kennedy,
and I am concerned.
(grunts)
This is not in keeping with
the spirit of pride week.
Alright, back off,
or my gang will ram me
into your stomach again.
Meanwhile, some sea
turtles are trying to get by
to lay their eggs.
Fight direction
by William Shatner.
Hee-haw, hee-haw
I think this is ready to pop.
Let's, agh!
William Bendix to the rescue.
(slow trumpet music)
You have defeated me, sir.
You and your noble
band of choreographers.
Hank, I--
I want my pants back.
I think that we should...
So, do you want me to
keep taking my shirt off,
or is that moment
kind of, uh, over?
Come on, Mike.
Let's cut out.
Ah, now what are we gonna do?
What are we gonna watch now?
We're not ready
to go home yet.
Well, I'm gonna
strip for someone!
Owie, owie, owie, owie, owie.
Chiggers.
Ow, the sand's hot too.
Ow!
I can't get this beer open.
She uses the Art
Garfunkel hair care system.
She swims like Luis Tiant.
She's actually
going backwards.
(upbeat beach music)
Mark Harmon on drums.
Mice go!
(All chuckle)
Lower the camera.
Lower the camera!
I had a generally positive
impression of white people
before this movie.
I'm starting to agree
with the Taliban Militia.
Dancing should not be allowed.
Leopard skin pill box bra.
Bikini and a babushka.
That's nice.
Miss, could you
clear the shot please?
Miss!
Oh, right in my ear.
Six miles out, and I still
hear that awful music.
Cool, it's the Rosetta Stone.
Wow, Europe is
smaller than I thought.
A sexy Romulan girl.
I can't touch you.
You're a lady.
Doing the Going Mental dance.
(slamming impact vibrations)
Whee!
Bum, ba, bum, ba, bum, bum.
(Tom Servo chuckles)
Say, Mike.
You're ready for our
manly beach dance?
Manly beach dance time, Mike.
(Crow chuckles)
Uhh, yeah, well,
these trunks you made me
seem kind of small.
Oh, I'm sure they're fine.
Yeah.
No, they seem really small.
Hold on.
Let me show you.
I'll just come out here.
Just get comfortable
with your body, and.
Whoa, whoa, well,
well, well, well, then.
What do you think?
These are kinda small, right?
Mike, you're nude.
All nude, yep.
No, no, I got 'em on.
I just think they're
really small.
Especially when I dance.
Oh, no, Mike,
Mike, no, no, no, no.
Mike, Mike, Mike, Mike
are you sure you put 'em on?
No, they're on.
They're just (mumbles).
He's so nude. It's just...
The tag's in
back and everything?
Oh, that's probably it.
Hold on. Let me look.
(Mike grunts)
Yep, there it,
the tag's in back.
But I don't know.
Maybe it's the dancing.
No.
No, no, no, no.
Why don't you
just go a size up?
We've got some right here.
Oh, okay, let me try these on.
Maybe that's the problem.
Wow.
(Crow chuckles)
Yeah, I think those
are gonna be better.
Those are gonna, but
anyone think the dancing?
Nah, nah, no.
Go a size up, Mike, please.
Yes, we'll all feel a
lot more comfortable, Mike.
Okay, well, I'll slip into
these, and I'll show you these.
Then, we'll be able
to keep down our lunch.
My God, yes.
Take it easy, Crow.
We'll be right back, everybody.
Part of me will never be back.
(Tom Servo chuckles)
Part of me is gone forever, oh.
(upbeat pop music)
I don't see what
the problem is.
They fit rather well.
Ew, Lloyd Bridges
has not aged well.
(intense lurking music)
(upbeat beach music)
This band writes some
really long songs.
♪ Now everybody do
the Zombie Stomp
Go Romulan babe.
(upbeat beach music)
Can you guys make a loop
of this and show it for
about 30 hours?
Is that a diaper?
Heh, heh, it's
fun to have fun.
I don't care what they say.
I feel good about myself.
♪ And all the flesh
slipped off my skull
Ladies and gentlemen,
Scott Scrawny
and the Hard Gainers.
I'm wearing pull-ups, mommy.
All hail to Ra, the sun god.
Mike, are we being
punished for something?
Sniper.
Well, say what
you want about her.
At least she's not
doing the Zombie Stomp.
Oh, hi, grandma.
Ma'am, I'd like to report
some illegal waste dumping.
Are you a federal
agency by any chance?
That's it. I'm gonna make some
big changes this year.
After all, I've got a long,
full life ahead of me.
Heh, heh, it's fun to get a
tiny portion of my hair wet.
♪ I'm on a rock.
♪ I'm on an island.
Cookie.
(woman screams)
Get your hotdogs.
Relax ma'am.
I am a licensed doctor
of chiropractic.
(woman screams)
Do you think a lot of
guys who make movies have
issues with women?
Could be.
♪ I slept the whole
night through
Swim suit by the
Mike Douglas show.
Do you believe that
kissing is unhealthy?
I don't know.
I've never been...
You've never been kissed?
No, I've never been sick!
I just wanted to tell you
I was recently diagnosed
as having, oh, never mind.
Well, I better get my laps in.
You know, monsters
can dog paddle at
a horrifying rate.
(water splashes)
Offshore, the Normandy
Invasion Force waits patiently.
It's amazing they can
get such rich sound without
plugging in their instruments.
Uhh, isn't there a
union rule that says they
have to take a break?
Nair side, foam side.
Nair side.
♪ What good is a man
♪ If he's thin as a brooohhhoom.
I want my Peter
Allen albums back.
Hiya, Charlie.
Do you like bathing beauties?
No, ick!
I don't know.
I never bathed one!
(men laugh)
(woman screams)
It's Chris Farley in a thong!
(people yell)
Look out,
Ted Kennedy's driving home!
Mmm, grandpa lost his
suit in the water again.
Oh, someone went in the ocean.
I hope that's a Clark bar.
(woman gasps)
Boy, that siren got us through
some pretty rough traffic.
Thanks for coming
out to help me.
My pipe's stuck in my mouth.
Hi, do you have
any spare pork?
We're hungry.
- Morning.
Nice morning.
No, it isn't.
Looks like a clear day.
No, it doesn't.
I was just looking at
that little cloud up there
by the sun and
thinking it might rain.
I guess everybody interprets
the world according to
his own mood.
Well, no weather is
good for a funeral.
In my business, I
try to avoid them.
Too bad he's an undertaker.
Elaine, it's 9:30.
Mother Angelica is on.
I guess she'd be abnormal
if she were on time.
How's she taking it?
It's not easy for any of us.
A lot of families have
been affected by this.
Helps her to know
she's not alone.
Here's the sample
that you asked for.
Could you have
put it in something?
I'm gonna run some carbon-14
tests on this tissue.
There have been some recent
discoveries in the field
of genetics that may give
us a clue to its structure.
Good luck, doc.
Thanks. Bye.
Heh, heh, this is going
straight up my nose.
Well, hit the siren.
Shakey's lunch buffet awaits.
We had to get a
door from a junk yard.
(car siren)
Oh, you're ready.
Why is the car
in the living room?
You do understand why I'm
not going, don't you, dear?
Of course, daddy.
Everybody knows how hard
you've been working.
You gonna pick
up Hank on the way?
Why am I dubbed?
Yes.
Daddy, I'm so
upset about Hank.
Hardware Hank?
Here I am going to Tina's
funeral, and I have such
feelings about him.
What kind of feelings?
I don't know.
Lay off!
Is it because he's free now?
They don't have
to work you over.
Yes, I suppose so.
You go ahead, dear.
I'll just smell
your forehead goodbye.
(car door slams)
That car has like
12 cigarette lighters.
It's a human thing, Dr. Gavin.
You wouldn't understand.
It's a human evil thing
lurking and creeping and
crawling around out
there in the night.
I know it. I feel it.
Mother, please.
You musn't talk like that.
A great deal of the ocean
is still a mystery to us.
There are undoubtedly
forms of life that we know
nothing about.
Like me.
It's that voodoo.
That's what it is.
Now that's
ridiculous, Eulabelle.
I want you to get this idea
of voodoo out of your head.
Try snake handling instead.
I have no doubt that we'll
find a perfectly reasonable
explanation for the
girl's death.
Like giant squirrels.
Maybe you're right.
But the police have been
looking, and they haven't
found anything.
They been running round
here like headless chickens.
And you been
looking and reading.
And what have you found?
Nothing is solved
in a few hours.
This will require
a lot of research.
And while you're researching,
there's something creeping
and crawling and lurking
around out there.
That's enough.
You're scaring me.
I understand.
I'll have my things
packed by the morning.
It's some voodoo,
that's what it is.
Ha, you non-Caucasians.
You'd better go
to bed, Eulabelle.
But I just got up.
Did you lock up?
Locked, double locked,
and triple locked.
Ain't no monsters gonna
get in here tonight.
Ugh, why did I fire Hazel?
It's some voodoo alright.
Alright, I'll strangle
a chicken if it'll
make you happy.
(upbeat pop music)
Let's see here:
How to Kill That Spark of Life.
Chapter One - Joy: Who Needs It.
No, maybe.
Ah, here we are: Getting
Girls Through Hypnosis.
Yes, yes, yes.
Hi, daddy.
You betrayed me, Fredo.
I thought you were
going out tonight?
Oh, I was, but it's just
another slumber party.
They're all the same, so I'm
not really missing anything.
Did you let 'em know
you weren't coming?
No.
Don't you think you should?
Oh, Daddy, I just don't
see how you can even think of
such a thing after
what happened to Tina.
Roast in Hell, Dad.
Tina's death has affected
a great many people.
But it doesn't give you
or anyone else the right to
be discourteous.
Oh, ram it, bozo.
Oh, alright.
I'll go telephone.
Well, let's start
mopping the ceiling.
(Crow chuckles)
That's not how
you make sun tea.
Okay.
I'm happy I was invited, heh!
(bell rings)
Battle stations.
Ahhhh!
Hit the deck.
Man the torpedoes.
Hello.
It's for Libby.
Libby.
I think they just filmed
an actual slumber party.
Yeah, bummer.
Hi, Elaine. Where are you?
The actual summit of K2?
Why?
Oh, Elaine, you're
gonna miss all the fun.
Oh, Elaine, we've got secret
information that the boys
from the Chi Psi House
are going to crash.
We've got a big bucket
rigged up over the door.
And I can't wait to see
Ricky Aldridge as he comes
through the door and
gets it spilled on him.
(Mike chuckles)
Oh, Elaine, please come.
It'll be so much fun.
Boy, Elaine, you don't
have to call me a bitch.
Well, okay. Alright.
I understand. Goodbye.
Goodbye, Libby.
I don't like slumber parties
now that I'm in my 40s.
I'm glad I called, Daddy.
It was the right thing to do.
♪ Oh, hard is the fortune
of all womankind
This better be
a strip folk song.
♪ They're always controlled
Stop it.
They've only been together
a couple of hours, but
they're all already
on the same cycle.
Never invite Janis Ian
to your slumber party.
♪ And slaves to their husbands
Can I sit in?
I brought my baritone horn.
(intense vibration music)
I forgot my nightie.
You're a cute couple.
Suddenly I feel like
gossiping and eating
popcorn all night.
You?
(girls singing)
So, they put "The
Second Sex" to music.
There's no reason
to leave C, I find.
Do not use poison
ivy for toilet paper.
Believe me.
We are trying to spawn.
(girls laughing)
(Mike chuckles)
The Ipswich Women's Club
presents Shirley Jackson's
"The Lottery".
Come on.
I think we're
gonna get killed.
Neat.
[One Of The Girls]
What are they doing?
I smell something awful.
It smells like dead fish.
[One Of The Girls] Ew, I hope
they don't throw fish again.
Like they did last year.
[One Of The Girls]
Shhh! Quiet girls!
Concentrate on sticking
your fannies out.
[One Of The Girls]
Everybody keep quiet.
I'll turn off the lights.
Oh, hi.
We're the lobsters you selected.
True to her word.
She turns off the light.
- Wow.
- Wow, man.
Hi, Jehovah's Monsters.
Please take a Watchmonster.
Okay, boys. The door's open.
(girls giggle)
Ah, ha, ha.
You gals got something
planned, don't you?
(girls giggle)
Carnival of Coeds.
(rumbling growl)
(door crashes open)
Oh, monster on the floor.
Monster on the floor.
Don't even know what panties
are, yet they feel compelled
to raid.
Every male of any species
has the biological urge
to panty raid.
Oh, great party, Janice.
Thanks.
I really wanted to be dead.
(rumbling growls)
Ahh, I forgot my train case.
I'm heavy. Right?
Sorry, I pigged
out on Häagen-Dazs.
There's more chips
if anyone wants them.
Rumors of an invasion from
the sea took on a new dimension
last night when over 20 teenage
girls were brutally attacked
and murdered during
a slumber party.
Ah, great, the kids
should love this.
A survivor described these
monsters differently from
those which terrorized the
beach only a few days ago.
But Dr. Gavin,
special consultant
for the police, suggested
that these beings probably have
different forms in the same
way that human beings
vary in size and shape.
And pants.
Meanwhile, specialists from
all over the United States
converged on our city in an
attempt to piece together
the scattered
reports of attacks.
Archibald Cox.
In a massive effort to find
out the identity of these
strange creatures from the sea.
Extra, extra.
Read all about it.
50's extended indefinitely.
Extra, extra.
Read all about it.
Oh, my goodness.
Is Abby running "Please
God, I'm Only 17" again?
This scene alone is better
than the whole movie "Newsies".
Thank you. Thank you.
But not you.
President orders
monsters back to work.
Are considered
smelly and dangerous.
Listen, we better
skip this town.
This is the place where
they're having all the trouble.
Cops?
No, murders by the hundreds.
Some kind of monsters
killing people and drinking
their blood.
Ahh!
Eww, it gives me the creeps.
Imagine, being that thirsty.
(Crow chuckles)
Oh, very funny, Miss Ghoul.
I read all about
it in the papers.
This town's too
hot for my blood.
What, are you a gecko?
Well, you know what I mean.
Listen girls.
I need some gas.
We better stop, and we'll
get some directions, too.
City service is Citgo now.
Zoom, zoom, zoom, zoom, zoom.
Citgo zoom.
You watch too much TV.
(wheels screech)
Big hunk of inbred love.
Yes, ma'am?
Can I help you?
He's cute, isn't he?
- No.
Fill me up, huh?
Sure.
Yes, an entire tank of gas.
Score.
Well, golly.
(bell dings)
Can you tell these
are support hose?
Thoughts of sex distracted
me, and now I'll have to
immolate myself to subdue
the buzzing in my head.
Oh, well, that's
great, but come along.
(upbeat pop music)
And so, I said to Jupiter,
"You know that Saturn."
"He's a different kind of god."
(Man in red laughs)
It's a different kind of god.
Oh, more wine?
Yes.
Yes, yes, good, good.
It's from Gaul, you know.
You might say it's
from conquered grapes.
(Man in red laughs)
Oh, open a window.
We invented the pun, you know.
Is that right?
Goddess of Pearlo, from
what part of the Emperium
do you dwell, generally?
Uhh, the suburbs.
I believe Pliny speaks
of the suburbs of the gods.
And what are your godly gifts?
Earthquake?
Fire from the sky?
Music, perhaps?
Yes, music, music,
yes, definitely.
Well then, do favor
us with a song, lyres.
What did you just call me?
Oh.
Of course.
Umm, Brain Guygius, why don't
you take the auto harp here.
And I will take the
gourd with a stick.
Help me.
I can't play a lick.
Just smile and play along.
I'll save your bacon again.
Alright then, what shall
we start with today?
Maybe a bit of
Bitter Dregs, huh?
Sure.
Ah, we'll just jam
and see what happens.
(Brain Guy chuckles)
Okay, then.
Here we go.
(musical instruments play)
We're going.
By Jove, ha, ha!
Truly this is the
music of the gods.
Wha-hoo!
(Man in red laughs)
Come, let us dance.
No, Calipigeous.
You'll love it. It's the gods.
Ohh!
(musical instruments play)
Hoedown.
Everybody.
♪ In Asia Minor, it's
a spicy beef salad
♪ In Pompeii, sizzling
beef pot stickers
♪ In Iconia, a rich
kettle of beef stew
♪ In Gaul, it's rich
beef Chateau Briand
Demigods, join us.
Beef, it's what's
for movie sign.
We got movie sign.
(impact vibrations)
Say, what's this I hear
about all these murders you've
been having around here?
Oh, yeah, it's a big deal.
They got a big
investigation going on.
They got guys coming up here
from Washington and everything.
Hey, we better get
out of here, girls.
You aren't kidding.
Hey, handsome, what's the
fastest way to get to New York?
Rocket car.
Well, I guess the best way
is to, umm, go down here to
Wire Mill Road.
And you turn left, and
go two blocks over and...
You're in Manhattan.
Then, you turn right,
and you go past the quarry.
And you'll see the thruway
right on the other side.
You can't miss it.
Thanks.
How much do I owe ya?
That's $4, please.
And a peek at your bra.
Thanks, honey.
You're welcome.
You want your Dick
Butkus collectible mug?
(car engine turns)
In that case, if you
girls ever want to make good
on your innuendo, please
feel free to stop by.
Turn left. Turn left.
Look at this route.
I can't look, stupid.
I'm driving.
You want to crack us up?
Take a right on Monster
Killing Girls Road.
(car tires screech)
Here we go!
New York or bust!
Can you just fast
forward to the death?
Wow, Herald Square.
This is a road?
(tire pops)
Heh, heh, you know what
that tire's favorite opera is?
Deflater Maus.
Oh, great, a flat tire.
Right in the
middle of rush hour.
Extra footage
supplied by Zapruder.
Now what do we do?
Well, this is New York.
We should be able to hail a cab.
I hope we see Woody
Allen while we're here
in New York.
I think we need to
rebuild the engine.
I just saw "Rent".
Hey, where ya been?
Bo needs help with the wheel.
Down by that quarry.
Something must've died in there.
It smells like the Fulton
fish market in the middle
of July.
(intense thumping music)
Hey, I put on a
bunch of patchouli oil.
I smell just fine.
(intense music)
How's it goin', hon?
Well, I got it off,
but I can't see nothing.
How 'bout some help?
Okay.
They're headed to the
Laverne DeFazio convention.
Hey, hold it, you two.
What's with you?
I heard something.
It sounds like the
opening percussion to the
Olympics theme.
Aw, if it ain't money rustling,
it ain't worth hearing.
Shh! Hold it.
I hear something too.
That monster's
pronating badly.
Sounds like somebody,
somebody big, walking in mud.
Joe Don Baker?
You two flipped your
wigs or something?
It's a wiglet.
So, this is the touring
company of "Come Back to the
Five and Dime, Jimmy
Dean, Jimmy Dean".
Hello, monster.
Want to exchange innuendos?
(Tom Servo chuckles)
It's just those famous
Mexican walking catfish.
(intense music)
There's that fishy smell again!
Could it be Babe Winkelman?
I think I'll go
take a look around, girls.
I'm in my constricting
skirt and high heels,
so I should be
perfect monster bait.
(screeches)
Oh, isn't that just
like Denise to meet a guy.
Please stop eating me
when I'm a size eight, okay?
Hi-ya, hi-ya-ha.
They're slightly less attractive
than our regular boyfriends.
Tonight on "Roar"...
Come on. We'll ditch my
girlfriends, come on.
(girl screams)
Yeah, that sounds
like a solenoid.
Pop the hood, and we'll
take a look at it.
Okay, watch the body.
Don't watch the head.
Oh, alright. Got her.
The day the mudskippers
fought back.
The movie's unflinching
look at women from New York
is its best feature.
I could pay my own
way into the drive-in.
Now, ow!
Ow, ow, pop the trunk!
Pop the trunk, ow!
(intense music)
Filmed inside a deacon's hat.
(growling)
And, sadly, a gas
attendant's dream
goes unfulfilled.
(growling)
The next morning at
the monster's home.
Look at all the toenails.
How many toenails?
It doesn't even
have this many toes.
Toenails everywhere.
Whoo!
Move your feet ya load.
I've had my share of the
misery too, Miss Elaine.
And I know what it is.
Three brothers and two sisters
all dead and gone.
But you don't see me going
around moaning and groaning
all day.
I have my work.
And the Lord has his,
and he takes care of us
wherever we are.
Yawn!
Why, what's this, Eulabelle?
Oh, that's mine.
Give it to me.
So dubbed.
It's a voodoo doll.
Isn't it?
You really believe in it.
Now don't you go
teasing, Miss Elaine.
I know a lot more
things than I say.
Eulabelle, there's no
such thing as voodoo.
Yeah, ask any Haitian.
Who is it anyway?
It's my Oscar Gamble doll.
One of them zombies.
Al Gore?
Dr. Gavin was so worried.
I thought I could help.
She's got Dilbert's
boss's hair.
Well, somebody's
got to do something.
(doorbell rings)
Oh, I'm black. I'll get it.
Hello, Mr. Hank. Come in.
Hello, Eulabelle.
Just rode in from Richmond.
Here's that nice young
boy just pining to take
you out.
Take you right
out of the picture.
(Tom Servo chuckles)
Now quit your moaning
and groaning and go out and
have some fun.
Your father didn't need
me this afternoon, Elaine.
And, well, I thought maybe
you'd like to go for a drive
or something.
What do you think magic bear?
Oh, I don't know, Hank.
Now, go on
upstairs and change.
He'll wait.
Just smile at the
stupid white people.
Look, I don't mind waiting.
You go ahead and change.
Alright.
Meanwhile, the monster gang
pulled into their safe house
in Columbus, Ohio.
How'd you like to
take a drive down
Long Street, huh?
Why did you come back
to the beach, Hank?
I don't know, Elaine.
Stuff, I guess.
I had a funny feeling
about this place.
I get it at my
aunt's place too.
Come on. Let's go.
Huh, I wonder where he went?
Oh.
Oh, she made her dress
out of a table runner.
Oh, for cute.
So, who's that bald,
pipe-smoking idiot who's always
wandering around your house?
Oh, I'm sorry.
That's your dad.
Hey, man, what's happening?
How ya doin' gang?
Pretty dead tonight, huh, Ron?
Yeah, ever since Tina
got killed, like no action
around here.
Yeah, well, it'll pick up.
That's so wise.
- Take it easy, man.
- Take it easy.
Alright, here we go.
Mmm bop, ding a ding da mmm bop.
Boo-be be be be ba bop.
Ron, what are you gonna play?
What would you
like to hear, Elaine?
How 'bout "You're
Not A Summer Love"?
Mmmm, just for you, baby.
Mmmm, hear that?
Just for me, huh?
Hi!
Help, we're cutouts!
♪ Summer love, summer love
Huh, first you deny
the grief, then party!
Margaret Chase Smith
running for senate.
I'd like your vote.
♪ You are not a summer love
Whoo, almost had fun there.
Better watch myself.
♪ Give me mine, give me mine
Hey, Mars exploded. Huh.
♪ You are not a summer love
♪ You are a summer sausage.
And then, I almost didn't
call about not attending
the slumber party.
Hey, wait, come back.
♪ To love me ever
♪ I say forever
Okay, go for your gun.
♪ That you will be endlessly
Scanners
I'd say something,
but the guy who dubs me
is on break.
Do you like cheese?
♪ I'll be true
I am comprised of a
series of ones and zeros.
Like a blank tape.
Never even cracked the seal.
Oh, Hardware.
♪ Oh, my darling, tell me
♪ Tell me you'll
be mine forever
♪ I never touched a woman.
♪ We make the saints cry.
♪ Love me forever
Or I'll kill you.
♪ I say forever
♪ That you will be
Yes, the sweeping majesty of
young white Republican love.
♪ Close to me like
the sand and the sea
Are we dead?
Hey, enough, enough touching.
That's enough.
There must be five car
lengths between couples.
♪ I'll be true
♪ To you
Come on.
I want to take you
over to the buffet.
They have this German potato
salad I want you to see.
♪ Oh, my darling
So, my parents were
born when they were young.
♪ Tell me you'll
be mine forever
I was at the
slumber party, and I have
a lot of survivor--
mmm... mmm... mmm...
I'll never kiss again.
Well, I guess I never
have, pretty much.
(Crow chuckles)
Thanks for the free Funyuns.
Good night, girls.
Now you go straight home.
My brother's
coming to pick us up.
Good night, now.
Good night, Johnny.
Anytime you close
down a drugstore, it's a
wild night.
Uh-heuh!
I think they're from
the ladies' volunteer
inventory-taking guild.
Ssss, hey lady.
Lady.
Would you buy me some beer?
I don't have ID.
Look Polish?
What? Huh?
Look at the sign up there.
(intense music)
He's not coming. Let's walk.
There, see?
Look Polish.
Or, maybe it's look, Polish.
(intense music)
(girls gossiping)
They're using their
Flintstone voices.
Anyway.
(Mike mumbles nonsense)
So, why are they
speaking in tongues?
No, he's not
Yeah.
Yeah, well, my
mother (mumbles).
Well, I knew a guy who did that.
Baby Bop's a prowler.
(girls gossiping)
Will you two shut up?
(car horn honks)
Come on. Come on.
It's Steve Allen.
Don't get in.
(intense music)
Debbie, why don't
you sit in back.
Oh, okay. Up front's okay.
(growling)
Stupid, stupid, stupid.
What was I thinking that
she'd ever go out with me?
(Crow cries)
(intense music)
(Tom Servo sings a tune)
Linda?
Oh, if only I wore a size six.
I can't see the price.
Where's the price?
(glass breaks)
After the King verdict,
monsters looted boutiques.
Well, just take the
glove off (mumbles).
(intense music)
(groaning)
(glass clanks)
Mmm, he's got a delicious
blue cheese filling.
[Mike] Ick!
It's still alive.
I want to make some notes.
Yes sir.
This proves it.
Worms play pinochle
on your snout.
Hmmm, Monty Hall and
Bruno Hauptmann stopped by.
April 10th, 7 p.m.
Notes on possible
malignant organism.
Overall configuration:
That of a human arm severed
just below the elbow joint.
Muscle tissue seems
to be a sea anemone.
Species of protozoa.
These organs are exactly
like human organs except that
they have been replaced
by the protozoans.
Of course,
I'm high.
This creature needs
the ordinary necessities
of human life: proteins,
fats, sugars, and so forth.
None for me, thanks.
But since its organs are
so decomposed that they can
neither produce nor retain
the oxygen necessary for
its survival,
it needs the only food
which can keep it alive.
Oh, you mean me.
Right?
Blood?
Human blood.
Oh, we got some in the fridge.
If a human body, a drowned
person, were attacked
by tiny sea plants which
became parasites and completely
infiltrated that human
body before it had a chance
to decompose, would the body
be considered dead or alive?
The Beatles.
Dead?
No, it's still alive.
But it's changed into a...
Dip of some sort.
Well, is it a
plant or an animal?
Planimal.
It's both.
It's a giant protozoa.
Dr. Gavin.
What's the best foot cream?
Can they be killed?
Or at least spayed?
I don't know, lieutenant.
They are the living dead.
They're zombies.
The living dubbed.
[Dr. Gavin] Nothing so
dramatic as that, Elaine.
They're more like a jellyfish.
You can't kill them by shooting
them or cutting them up.
Well, then how
can you kill them?
Shh!
I want to make sure
the kids are down.
I hear something.
He's coming. Look
Polish, everyone.
The director bravely
mixes tedium
with unscariness.
Mom, can we stay up later?
(intense music)
There's something out there.
I know there is.
Alright now, everybody
just keep calm, and be quiet.
The gun won't help.
Here. Take these knives.
They're all we have.
They won't help either.
Elaine, over there
in that corner.
You need a timeout.
Lieutenant, when I
say lights, turn 'em on.
And I'll take care of this one.
See, I did it.
I didn't need any help.
Want to see me do it again?
Doctor, would this
be an appropriate time
to wet them?
(Crow gasps)
Mother Teresa?
Obi-wan Kenobi?
Leon Spinks?
(Crow chuckles)
[Dr. Gavin] Lights!
Eulabelle.
Oh, well, what are all of
you doing sneaking and peeking
in the dark?
I'm afraid you gave
us quite a scare.
Oh, I'm sorry, Dr. Gavin.
Is the little baby gonna cry?
It's so quiet up
there in the house.
I get scared by myself
all alone at night.
And them zombies, they
comin' at me tonight.
Eulabelle.
I just know they will.
(Eulabelle screams)
(glass clanks counter)
(gaseous explosion)
Opa!
You dope.
Now go get us
another monster arm.
That is bold barbecue.
Whoo!
Look, it's burning up!
Eulabelle, you've killed it.
Oh, Dr. Gavin, I'm sorry.
I didn't mean to.
No, don't be sorry.
This is wonderful.
You've discovered a way to
destroy these creatures.
And you're fired.
Lord, lord.
Look, completely dehydrated.
Neat.
Protozoans are
almost all water.
This is all we have left.
Well, there's more
in the car, but...
But what makes all the
smoke and steam, Daddy?
Sodium, plain old sodium.
Hank, you remember
your chemistry.
Sodium is a very unstable
metal that reacts violently
with water.
That's right.
Then they can be killed.
With sodium.
Ouch!
They can if we can find them.
(upbeat pop music)
And the monster search
goes way off-track.
Same to you, fella.
What about that guy, huh?
I just thought all-nude
was a dress code.
This is the reality
of Northwest Airlines'
"mechanical problems".
We are unwanted.
Outcasts.
Orphan of the storm.
What storm?
The storm of my soul.
He likes liquor
is what he means.
Right.
Well, we better get
back to the senate.
This is really fun.
This is exactly what
I wanted to do tonight.
Are we gonna raise the
spectre of wife swapping?
(Crow chuckles)
Where do we go now?
We'll drive.
Are you capa-able of driving?
Of course I'm capa-able.
Are you capa-able?
Of course I am.
Where's the car?
Thata way.
Albert Vitti permittee?!
(Mike chuckles)
Aha, I'll get my car.
You wait here.
I'll get my car.
We can listen to our
Foster Brooks books
on tape.
Can we drink our cars?
Well, the intervention
did not go off as planned.
These are the kind of
guys who wake up in pools
of various things.
It's odd that MADD would
invest in this movie.
- You think?
- Very well.
Okay, Joke coming
in on runway seven.
Joke, you have been
cleared for landing.
And... good.
(cars crash)
Hey, buddy.
You got Chrysler
on my Chevrolet.
You got Chevrolet
on my Chrysler.
I guess we weren't
capa-able-ble.
(men chuckle)
Can the monsters
kill these guys three
or four times?
Some people get giggly
when they drink.
Other people get
hateful and psychotic.
(Man laughs and yells)
Who's screaming?
Where are the demons?
Beelzebub.
Hey, lead the way.
Uncle (mumbles).
Let's go over to
Michael Irvin's place.
(men laugh and yell)
Ted Kennedy and
Bishop John Roach.
Hey, what's that sound?
Well, I'm urinating.
(Man chuckles)
That's you.
It is? No, it's you.
(intense music)
I think I hear Oberon.
Let's hear you walk.
Otis of Mayberry had a
quiet dignity compared to
these guys.
No, it's not you.
Now you walk.
Now I'll walk off
the screen and into
obscurity.
No, that's not you either.
Vladimir and
Estragon, the sitcom!
Hey.
Do farts have lumps?
(flatulence)
What's it sound like?
It sounds like somebody in-
in rubbers filled with water.
Are you wearing rubbers?
No.
These two are forbidden
to even say the word
rubber.
It's probably somebody who
came from the swimming pool
and came from
swimming with their...
Boy, the French would
love these two guys.
Genius.
That's not so funny.
It's probably some old drunk.
God, I hate drunks.
(mumbles)
I'm glad we were
able to remain friends
after our breakup, Tib.
They left their lights on.
Must be Tom Bodett.
Well, we better
go turn 'em off.
Yeah, save his battery
for Heaven's sake.
They're AA and Triple A.
Hey, Stan, there's
a guy in here.
And he looks Polish.
(Man chuckles)
Dead man breathing.
Hey, buddy.
Could I use your liver?
(Man chuckles)
What are you doing?
You sleeping?
You think it's funny to sleep?
Huh? Huh?
Oh, buddy.
(Man chuckles)
Ahh!
Hey! Hey!
Buddy! Buddy!
He couldn't get
his contact out.
Hey Stan, this guy
ain't got no face.
♪ Guy without a face...
♪ Got no human traits...
The vodka's in the, ugh!
Hey, Stan.
I better call 9-1,
what's the other number?
Stan, don't play
these games on me.
Blackness.
♪ Oompa loompa doompety doo
♪ I've got another
riddle for you
Serpentine.
(Tom Servo cries)
I love Lakers so much.
(roaring)
I care too much about you.
I've got to get you to detox.
Uh-oh!
What happens if the monster's
a recovering alcoholic?
Oh boy!
Because of this recent
discovery, the police now feel
certain that in a very short
time, a method will be found
to locate and destroy
these frightful monsters.
Extra, extra,
read all about it.
The birth of a media empire.
Rusty Murdoch.
(woman screams)
(growling)
Flex time a sticking
point in contract.
Monsters tease cat.
The monsters win the pennant!
Well, I could just run
out and get some sodium,
but I'm really beat.
Monster in tryst
with cabaña boy.
(intense music)
(girl screams)
(Mike chuckles)
You know what would
solve this problem?
More highway ramp meters.
(roaring)
Meanwhile, the police
are working around
the clock to get little
Suzy Johnson's bike back.
We offer this shot of a guy
leaving a building as proof
of how hard they're working.
Monsters re-killing
previous victims.
Authorities don't
know Shinola from that
other stuff.
Dr. Gavin, look.
It says this letter is
gonna need two stamps.
So, why aren't
they using sodium?
- Sodium.
Remember, boom, boom, sodium.
Sodium.
The water from that
arm is radioactive.
Dummies.
That means the cells
themselves are radiated.
But how?
Umm, voodoo, sir?
The floating pig.
The what?
That's what we call the
garbage scow that leaves the
harbor every week.
You see, it's been dumping
waste material from the reactor
at the university.
Do you know where they dump?
There's a loo on
the ship, I imagine.
A friend of mine said
he saw them once out at
Western Island, I believe.
Western Island?
It's over here
in the East right?
Here it is.
Look at these currents, Hank.
If one of those containers
sprung a leak, the waste would
be drawn right by our shore.
And that's where Tina was
killed that first night.
Western Island is also where
that fishing boat went down
just a few weeks ago.
I've dumped there often.
These creatures are human bodies
kept alive by radioactive decay.
Sodium.
So, wherever they go, they
leave radioactive water.
Try sodium.
So all we have to
do is to test the water....
Sodium.
...to know where they've been.
Sodium, sodium.
Right, then we can
tell where they are.
Sodium.
At this minute,
wherever they are,
It's your plot point.
they're building up a small
and harmless radioactive
residue in the
surrounding water.
The stuff that
burnt the monster arm.
Our Geiger counters will get
a scale 15 reaction out of
- that water.
- So-
D, I, U.
So, what we have to do
is just test all the water
in the immediate area.
M, sodium.
And if they're in one of
those lakes, well, we'll get
a scale reading
from the counter.
Sodium.
- Right. I'll call the police.
- Sodium.
We'll organize and get all
the people in the countryside
- to help us.
- Sodium.
Then, all we have to
do is find them, and sodium
will kill them.
Alright.
Yeah, yeah sodium.
You're right.
Say, Dr. Gavin.
D'oh!
We don't know
how many there are.
We might need tons of it.
You get on the phone and
call every chemical supply
company in the area.
Noooo!
Someone must carry
sodium in large quantities.
I'll call Lieutenant Wells
and get this thing started.
Geez, wow.
Sodium enters the movie.
We may stop these monsters
before another night
of killing.
Right, Dr. Gavin.
(impact vibrations)
Extree, extree.
Read all about it.
Hey, what's up, Tom?
Well, Mike, I was so impressed
by that plucky news boy
in the movie.
You know, out there every day
during the monster crisis,
getting people the
information they need to avoid
being eaten.
And his headlines were
always so darn up-to-date.
Yeah, that's true.
So?
So, what?
What, what?
D'oh, oh!
See I've gone into the
newspaper business.
(Mike and Tom Servo chuckle)
All the pertinent news our
satellite community needs
updated whenever a story breaks.
Hey, you want to buy
the latest edition?
Sure.
(Tom Servo chuckles)
Yextree.
Oh, "Mike Buys
Paper From Servo".
That's extremely
current, I'd say.
No, old news already.
Gotta get the next edition out.
Yextree, yextree, "Mike Buys
Another Newspaper From Servo".
Oh, that's cute.
So, it's a new headline
every couple seconds.
Yextree, yextree.
"Mike Chuckles at
Speed of News Updates".
Yeah, yeah, I guess I did.
Yextree, yextree, "Servo
Senses Mike's Growing
"Impatience with Newspaper Gag".
I think you nailed that story.
Yextree, yextree.
"Mike Getting
Really Annoyed Now".
I'd say that's true to
a certain extent because
I mean how am I...
Yextree, yextree, "Servo About
to Divert Mike's Attention
"and Make a Run for It".
I mean, you buy all these papers
just to come in and annoy me.
Mike, look behind you.
It's a giraffe with the
head of Larry Hagman.
What? Where?
What? Why?
Where's the giraffe with
the head of Larry Hag-?
D'oh, he fooled me.
We'll, uhh, we'll be
right back.
(upbeat pop music)
Ah, I wonder if he got
the sodium thing working.
Meat is good.
I really like meat.
You're right. Vegetables aren't
so good, but meat is good.
Good afternoon, gentlemen.
I have here a list of
meats I'd like to read.
Now, these are instructions
and map coordinates.
And meat recipes.
We need to break up
into separate teams.
Each team is to organize,
search in that specific area.
Will there be a
meat break, sir?
There are a limited
number of Geiger counters.
So share.
There's more being
brought up from New York.
So, don't worry about it.
You'll have them by the
end of the afternoon.
Now, only two of you will
actually get to meet McGruff.
I want you to find
every single body of water
in your area.
Like my bathtub, sir?
And be sure it's tested.
You've got to be sure that
those things haven't been there.
Let's get going.
McHale, your
water's dirty, McHale.
Stupid lake.
(intense frantic music)
This lake is pregnant.
Those frosted lips
are radioactive.
Whoo!
Uhh, any common tadpoles
on the current crisis?
I found the monster's
Caprice Wagon.
(intense trumpet music)
No sir, I never knew
the monster that well,
but I'll do what
I can to help you.
For the budget honeymooner,
try Frank's Discount Falls.
Let's see, Monster
Busters, Monsters Begone,
Screaming mad at Monsters.
How's it goin' Mr. Hank?
Oh, it's no use, Eulabelle.
Nobody has any sodium.
They all get their
supply on special order
from New York City.
Did you try everybody
in the telephone book?
Yeah, almost,
all but a couple.
(Mike chuckles)
Well, you try that couple.
Yeah!
You got to try, Mr. Hank.
Well, go on.
Alright, Eulabelle.
I'll call New York City.
They try throwing
Campbell's Soup?
That's got a lot
of sodium in it.
Hello, operator, would
you please get the Manhattan
Chemical Supply Company
in New York City?
You won't?
That's right.
The place without sodium.
Hello, listen, do
you carry any sodium?
Do you have it in loaden?
That's right, the metal.
You do?
Well, listen, listen,
do you have a lot of it?
Can I supersize it?
Well, will you
hang on to it for me?
You won't?
Hank Green.
Yeah, that's right.
Alright, I'll be there
in about an hour.
I'll have your
glasses ready too.
Well, I gotta buy a
window fan and do my tabs.
Then, I should swing by
and do that other thing
and pick up the life saving
sodium maybe before they close.
Ahh, I gotta bring that
one guy that thing, too.
How'd he get up there?
I think he's lost.
The ancient Sodium
Empire Exhibit at the Met.
He's in luck.
Whoo, hey where's
the Wonder Bra ad?
(jazzy upbeat music)
And down to Greenwich
Village for no reason.
Very lost.
How many more will die if
I do a little sightseeing,
four or five at most, right?
Is New York
closed for the day?
Wipeout.
I fooled 'em all.
I also run a chemical
supply warehouse.
(Tom Servo chuckles)
Well, I'd like to
help, but I've had this
dentist appointment
for six months.
Good afternoon, Dr. Gavin.
Good afternoon.
Saw you coming, so I
brought you some coffee.
Oh, good. Thank you.
Any sodium with that?
Any luck with your
water testing, Dr, Gavin?
Absolutely no luck.
I must have tested at least
10 places and didn't find
a thing.
Well, Mr. Hank found
that chemical whatacallit.
[Dr. Gavin] Oh, good.
And he's gone off
to New York to get it.
But he won't get
back before dark.
And Elaine? Where's Elaine?
Well, she's gone
off too, Dr. Gavin.
I think she mentioned
Fingle's Quarry.
- Fingle's Quarry?
- Yes, sir.
Take it back.
Good God, why didn't
I think of that before?
That's the deepest body of
water around here, and it's
right where those three
girls were killed.
And though it was
the most obvious place,
we haven't yet checked it.
When Hank gets here, tell him
I've gone to Fingle's Quarry.
Yes, sir.
And call the police and
tell them to meet me there.
Yes, sir.
And the Woolworth's Lunch
Counter, not that great.
Don't bother.
(phone dial spins)
Okay, where are my galoshes?
Galoshes, galoshes?
Oh, catch me some
lightning bugs while
I'm out there.
(car engine hums)
Resusci-Annie drives to
her next demonstration.
Fingle's Quarry.
Ah, there's Stingles Pulley.
Pringle's Folly.
Stinkle's Pinkhole.
Ringo's Fiddle.
Hinkle's Stinkwad.
Gingle's Mudfiddle.
Seward's Folly.
Finnegan's Rainbow.
Studs Lonigan.
That might be a
little far removed.
I'm just gonna imagine
the music that would
have added a lot to this scene.
Yeah.
So, to get the sodium,
I have to take their
old oil first?
He may be getting
too much sodium.
(Crow chuckles)
Stop.
Time to get to my
match with Krycek.
Bigfoot.
Big purse.
She's wearing her Eddie
Bauer rugged hiking skirt,
fully lined.
It does look quite
Fingle around here.
Okay, lake, you can disrobe
and hop up on the table now.
I'm meeting a lady
at the lake for brunch.
I visited the U.N.,
I had a nice lunch
with U Thant.
Calling car 28.
Pick up Hank Green.
He is coming East on
route 104 in gray MG.
And proceed to Fingle's Quarry.
Over.
Will do immediately.
♪ Doot doo doo doot doo
doo doot doo doot doot doo.
Okay, could you have one
of your walleyes fill this
for me, please?
Oh no, 0.4 misters per hour.
That bass down there
needs Beano real bad.
(woman screams)
Your Asian MILF oil.
Well, I better
mosey on out of here.
Kinda screamed too soon,
I guess.
What's his best feature?
Probably none.
What's with the bouzouki music?
(Mike chuckles)
(animated horn voice)
Are you Hank Green?
That's right.
Just follow me.
Why should I, pig?
(car engine buzzes)
(car siren)
Alright, sodium.
Clear the roads. We got sodium.
(intense music)
Well, I'm not gonna get
away from here tonight.
I better establish
base camp here.
(intense music)
(Tom Servo buzzes and hums)
(girl screams)
Ahh, I'm falling.
I'm falling again and
again and again and again.
Oh my gosh, I've placed
my leg against a rock.
The British Royal Family.
Oh, no!
(upbeat pop music)
(car siren)
I could carve a better
man out of a banana.
(growling)
Mommy, Mommy,
where are our towels?
We're getting cold.
Uh-oh!
She has her foot
caught in "The Rock".
(intense music)
How did she mutilate
herself so bad?
Is a little mouse down
there jabbing at her
with a toothpick?
(Mike chuckles)
Now, you're sure you
can't see my head kinda
protruding from my neck?
No, no, no. You'll be fine.
Well, alright.
(growling)
(barking)
The catch and release
program backfired horribly.
(growling)
Damn, the monsters
are tailing me.
It's the ice cream truck.
- Ice cream!
Whoo, I love ice cream!
(intense music)
Oh, I could have
lifted it out of there
the whole time.
I wonder why I
stayed here so long?
Gettysburg, the sec--,
oh wait, Fingle's Quarry. Sorry.
(intense music)
Oh, great, and I've got
that ass kicking contest
today, too.
Chop, chop. Chop, chop.
Cho, cho, cho, cho, cho,
cho, ta da la, chop, hey.
Sooooooooodiummmmm...
Soooooodiummmmm....
(intense music)
Wow, the sun burned
out between frames.
No, she's not a woman.
She's differently sexed.
What are we looking at,
and why are we looking at it?
(intense music)
(Crow chuckles)
Turns out I had some
sodium in my sock drawer.
(Crow chuckles)
(groaning)
Oh, hang on.
Gotta get the phone.
They could have used Hormel
chili or some Dinty Moore.
There's a lot of sodium in that.
(Mike chuckles)
(growling)
Cookie. Me want cookie.
Hey, hey, hey, you
spill my drink, buddy? Huh?
(Mike chuckles)
Well, meanwhile, later,
yesterday afternoon
I guess.
Where the hell are we?
Dad, I want to go to Vassar.
Not now.
(intense music)
(car siren)
Hey, they must've gone
the speed of light
'cause they can see
themselves arriving.
(car sirens)
(Tom Servo humming)
Quick set of doubles anyone?
(intense music)
Oh, no, we've got driveway
blacktop by mistake.
(growling)
A herd of salamanders.
Bosco puts hustle
in your muscle.
Bosco puts whee in your knee.
It also puts a dash
in your eyelash.
(growling)
(intense music)
Oh, hi, Dad's getting killed.
Hey, did you get to MoMA?
No! They must have tried
those last couple places
in the phone book.
And then they
drove to New York.
Retreat!
Damn you, Eulabelle!
You made them do it!
(intense music)
Dad's being smothered
by a huge loaf
of pepperoni-
studded brown bread.
(growling)
You brought beer?
(Tom Servo chuckles)
Sit down, Gomer.
(intense music)
Hey, pass that down, will ya?
Get your sodium!
Oh, the itching,
the horrible burning.
Oh.
Just at that moment,
a geyser goes off.
Wait, I come in peace!
I am the good- no,
wait a minute, I- ow!
(groaning)
God, this is fun.
Give me another one
of those things.
Ahh, my Richard
Pryor impression!
(crashing impact)
Guest appearance by
Commissioner Gordon.
(crashing explosions)
In a fever of killing,
they throw sodium at some
passing Girl Scouts.
(intense music)
What's that cop doing?
Get out of here.
Go on.
Just get out of here.
I'm dying.
Say, I got the
receipt for the sodium.
Could you pay me back now?
And we could split it five ways.
Of course, I spent money
on gas, too, didn't I?
Now, they got Gyuto monks.
Great.
And oh how they danced,
the little children
of Stonehenge.
Well, at least they
got compost to last
a few years anyway.
The Battle of Tinker's Belly.
(Mike chuckles)
Where's Shelby Foote
when you need him?
(police radio muffled)
(woman groaning and gasping)
Whoo! Wow!
Nasty.
(grunting)
(mumbles)
- Servo!
- Okay, alright, okay.
Well, 914 Long Street.
This is the place.
He never paid
me for the sodium.
I'll take it right
out of their...
We interrupt to bring you this
(mouth vibrations)
Oh, Mr. Hank, come in.
Hello, Eulabelle.
Just arrived on
the river boat.
Say, is Miss Elaine
receiving today?
I think she's asleep.
Let's check.
Alright.
Any news from the Northern
War Of Aggression, Eulabelle?
She's dressed like
Colonel Sanders.
We interrupt this
program of burning melodies
to bring you a special bulletin.
Shh, she's dead.
Late last night, our
police force, with the
assistance of
Dr. Richard Gavin...
Just jump right in with her.
...the hiding place of
the monsters from the sea.
Look, he's nude already.
(mumbles) ensuring all
citizens that the invasion
of the Seas army is over.
How are you, my darling?
I'm back from Bull Run.
Hank.
Hello, darling.
How's the leg?
Oh, it's much better.
I just saw your father,
and he's been burned badly
but he'll be fine.
And he'd be back from the
hospital within a week.
Oh, thank God.
Oh sure.
Just make yourself at home.
As far as you're
concerned, I'm wearing
a female condom.
Pants, several kevlar
undergarments, tiny pitbulls,
and motion detectors.
(upbeat music)
Oh, Hank.
I'm engaged to
The Del-Aires now.
The Eric Roberts voodoo doll.
♪ What good is a man
The music's coming
from inside the radio!
♪ Then, what good am I
♪ If I don't have you
Well, you don't have me, okay?
♪ Love me true
Del-Aires later
successfully broke up and went
to junior college.
♪ I don't want to be lonely
♪ I don't want to be blue
♪ But I can't help it
♪ If I don't have you
They all just got off
their shift at Rax!
(Mike chuckles)
He's not here!
♪ What's my baby's name
Oh wait, there was
a Tina in this movie?
Let's watch it again.
I love Tinas.
♪ But I love her just the same
♪ What good were the stars
Mova houta heavo?
♪ Then what good am I
I think they stole this
music from black people.
Well, black people were
gonna throw it away anyway.
♪ Love me true
Buddy Holly will
sue-uu--uu-ue!
The guy in the middle
better finish quickly.
He has a beating to get to.
♪ La la la la la la
Don't do that!
Wow!
Yeah, well end more.
It's not ending enough.
(impact vibrations)
Hey, everyone.
You know, Tom and Crow and
I were talking about how
the kids today don't
know squat about sodium.
Yeah, I couldn't have
put it better myself, Mike.
Why the shocking lack of sodium
taught in the schools today
is shocking.
That's right, Crow.
So, we asked ourselves how, how
do we reach kids today about
sodium?
How, how, how?
Through the rock n' roll
music that the kids seem
to like.
Yeah!
Hit it!
♪ - Sodium, sodium...
- sodium, sodium
♪ Sodium, sodium
♪ Soooooo diiiuuummm
♪ Sodiuuum
♪ Sooodiuum
♪ Sodium
♪ Sooodiium
♪ Soodiuuum
Sodium.
Sodium
Ah, if you don't know
anything about sodium now,
I don't know what
else we can do for ya.
Yeah, you kids with
your big pants, and your
colored chalk, and
your Neve Campbell.
Sodium, won't you?
And your fanny packs,
and your Nerf balls.
Oh, we better see
what's going on with Pearl
and them, huh?
Pong and your
Volkswagon Golf leases.
You ready?
And your notebooks, and
the kids with the pierced
I don't know what.
The roller skates, and the
23 skiddos, and the listening
to the Becks.
Mmmm!
(Man in red chuckles)
Now, that was a
glorious feast, aha!
Satiated, Brain Guyus?
Oh, yes indeed.
Well, then, puke?
Oh, no, thank you.
I'm really quite full.
No, I mean to the
Vomitorium, shall we?
Oh, ha, of course.
You son of a god.
(mumbles).
Be right back.
We'll be right back.
Eghhh!
Dah!
Oh!
(man in red chuckles)
You and women.
You know, I think I'm
really gonna like it here.
Say, be a dear, and have
one of your fellow servants
bring up more lamb.
Sure.
You know, I find it
so refreshing
that a woman your age
can still get blemishes.
It's cute.
Your plainness must afford
you a peaceful anonymity.
You're lucky.
Tell me, is that pile of
straw on your head easier
to care for than real hair?
(woman in yellow chuckles)
You, you are so
brave to wear that.
Even with all those black
goat hairs sticking out
of all the moles on your back.
Tell me, is your husband
so pale because you suck
the life blood out of him?
He's not my husband.
Oh, then you're barren.
No, just selective.
Must be fun to be a slut,
though.
(woman in yellow chuckles)
Not nearly as much fun as
being a boozed-up old hag!
That tears it.
(glass breaks)
(women chuckle)
I mean to think...
I know.
Your good wine bottle.
(women chuckle)
Skank.
Skag.
Oh, Flavia.
(men chuckle)
Flavia, the gods have deigned
to stay with us indefinitely.
Isn't it wonderful?
Beef!
(men chuckle)
(slow instrumental music)
(upbeat beach music)